# **Jacob Szepsy**

# **OBJECTIVE**

My goal is to make a transition from the information technology field to the computer science field and gain experience in software engineering. I'm heavily focused on software development and engineering which is reflected in my heavily computer science skewed course load. I also maintain a focus on systems integration and maintenance which is a useful asset to pair with my programming knowledge.

## **EDUCATION**

**New Jersey Institute of Technology** — BS Information Technology BS/MS Computer Science

2020, Newark NJ GPA 3.89

Ocean County College - AS General Studies Computer Science

2018, Toms River NJ GPA 3.45

# **RELEVANT COURSES**

Data Structures and Analysis, Systems Integration, Deep Learning for Games, Creative AI, Java Programming I and II, Introduction to Python, Networking, Principles of Operating Systems, Computer Architecture.

# **NOTABLE PROJECTS**

Full List Available at github.com/JacobSzepsy

#### ReactForums - Multi

2020

Custom forum software designed using React.js as a frontend that allows users to create and interact with threads on multiple boards. Used Ruby on Rails for the backend to create a RESTful API for the frontend to interface with.

Web service that allowed users to keep track of their favorite shows, get notifications when they were airing, and talk about them in an online forum. Written using LAMP stack. Responsible for frontend, backend, and database work as well as served as project manager.

#### **E2E Chat** - Java

2020

Chat service that provided end to end encryption for users. Responsible for writing the client side and encryption system.

## Tic Tac Toe Ai - Python

2019, Won Best Use of Google Cloud Platform at HackHERS 2019

Created an artificial intelligence using reinforcement learning that learned to play tic tac toe against a human opponent.

## **Discord Chat Bot** – Python

2018, Won Best From Scratch Program awarded by FDM at HackNJIT 2018

General Discord chat bot that provided administrative functions such as banning and muting as well as entertainment functions such as playing music in voice channels.

#### Twitch Chat Bot - Java

2016

Chat bot for streaming platform Twitch TV that allowed complete customization of every command via a basic scripting language created for the bot. All data is stored in a google spreadsheet allowing complete portability.

## **SKILLS**

Proficient with Java (single and multithreaded), Python (single and multithreaded), HTML, Javascript, Node.JS, CSS, PHP, Ajax. Experience with areas of artificial intelligence such as reinforcement learning, generative adversarial networks, and evolutionary algorithms. Very familiar with git and github. Experience working in both windows and unix based development environments.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# CVS Pharmacy - Supervisor

2019 - PRESENT, Lanoka Harbor NJ

- Increased sales of premium store memberships by 40%.
- Responsible for training 3 new individuals in the store.

#### **Private Tutor**

2016 - PRESENT

• Helped tutor several people in various CS concepts including web design, java programming, and general programming concepts

# NJIT - Research Assistant

2019 - 2019

• Assisted Dr. Amy Hoover in her work on the JaggySnakes project utilizing neural evolution of augmenting topologies.

# Bio Behavioral Health - Intern

2017 - 2018, Toms River NJ

- Upgraded all computer systems in the office to a more modern standard.
- Reduced the overall amount of computer issues in the office.

## **Awards**

## **Professional**

Employee of the Month - CVS August 2019

#### Personal

Best Use of Google Cloud Platform - HackHERS February 2019, Best From Scratch Program - HackNJIT November 2018

#### Academic

Dean's list Fall 2016, Spring 2017, Fall 2018, Fall 2019

# REFERENCES

Available upon request.